# **OLOWU BUSOLA OLUTAYO**

### **WEB DEVELOPER**

## **OBJECTIVE**

I am a solution-driven Web-Developer that excels in highly collaborative work environments, finds solutions to challenges and is focused on satisfaction. customer Proven experience developing consumerfocused web sites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux. MongoDB/PostgreSQL, Node and Express. Experience meeting the highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices, usability, and speed. Responding to challenges by developing solutions and building web applications aligned to customer's needs. Translating solutions into code and working across many different APIs, third-party integrations and databases.

#### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

#### **Birth date**

06/06/1992

## **Nationality**

NIGERIAN

## **Address**

No 1, Baptist Crescent, Idotun Ikenne Remo

## CONTACT

- codedcoderrr@gmail.com
- 07033305600
- https://codedcoder.com
- inkedin.com/in/codedcoder
- codedcoder

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

#### Intern

#### **HNG INTERNSHIP 6.0**

Sep, 2019 -Nov, 2019

An Internship organized by hotels.ng and sponsored by flutterwave that involves developing interns through collaboration, project management and also time management. I was team lead for two projects during the internship and I learnt valuable skills that have made me a better developer.

- I led a team into building a file sharing application, xshare.ga (built with MongoDB. Express, React/Redux, Node) that converts files, uploads them into a server and then converts them into sharable links. These links can be shared via email, socials(facebook,twitter,whatsapp) or it can just be copied directly and pasted as you see fit.
- I led a team into building a finance tracker application (built with MongoDB. Express, React/Redux, Node) that helps keep track of the user's expenses https://financetracker-triptolemus.herokuapp.com.
- I was part of the team that built trim.ng (built with MongoDB. Express, Node and EJS ), an application that shortens long links into short / customizable links.

## ICT Officer (NYSC)

## INTIMACY WITH CHRIST INTERNATIONAL SCHOOLS, NASARRAWA

2015-2016

- Managed IT facilities/assets and ensured all software and hardware problems were promptly attended to as they came up.
- Maintained the school's server and network and ensured all was running smoothly.
- · Worked with the Principal to resolve administrative problems and improve operation.
- Devoted special emphasis on punctuality and worked to maintain outstanding attendance record, consistently arriving to work ready to start immediately.
- Organized a club among students in order to encourage them into becoming responsible members of society

## **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Web Developer

**UDEMY** 2019

## BSC,COMPUTER SCIENCE(2ND CLASS UPPER'S DIVISION)

BABCOCK UNIVERSITY 2010–2015

# SKILLS

- React
- Redux
- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL

Javascript

- Express
- Node
- PHP
- Version Control(GIT)
- Testing
- V Html
- CSS
- Bootstrap

# ABOUT ME

- Problem solver
- Critical thinker
- Team Player
- Creative mind
- Reliable
- Excellent communicator
- Goal oriented
- Highly Dependable
- Hard worker